stop_name	imgURL	station_id	longitude	latitude	artist	title	media	artDate	Description	agency
Kimball	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/kedzie_vertglassart.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41290	-87.713065	41.967901	Josh Garber	Hope and Renewal	Powder-coated aluminum	2007	"Resembling architectural columns, this pair of sculptures depicts the lotus blossom, a universal symbol of hope and rebirth. Metaphorically, the flower-forms symbolize the aspirations of the Albany Park community, which is among the most diverse in Chicago. Artist Josh Garber hand-crafted these sculptures of thousands of aluminum bars and molded each petal of the lotus blossom to function as seating."	
Kedzie-Brown	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/francisco-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41180	-87.708821	41.965996	Anne Marie Karlsen	Round and Round	Art glass	2007	"Round and Round celebrates the historic and ongoing connection between the Kedzie station and the community. Anne Marie Karlsen achieved the kaleidoscopic motif by layering graphic imagery with color via photomontage. From a distance, the pattern of circles and semi-circles suggests the motion of train wheels, but a close look reveals images from historic photographs of train cars, the Kedzie station and the surrounding neighborhood."	
Francisco	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/rockwell-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40870	-87.701644	41.966046	Ellen Harvey	Carpet	Mosaic of hand-cut marble	2007	"Artist Ellen Harvey’s mosaic transforms an ordinary pathway into the image of an oriental carpet, a symbol of artistic and cultural exchange befitting the culturally diverse community surrounding the Francisco station. Just as a welcome mat serves as the transition between outdoors and indoors, the mosaic carpet symbolically links the station with the residential community, marking the transition between public and private spaces utilized by CTA riders"	
Rockwell	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/western-brown-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41010	-87.6941	41.966115	Thomas Skomski and Miklos Simon	Hidden Movers	Mixed Media	2007	"This composition of industrial and natural materials symbolizes the delicate relationship between nature and humankind. Photographs of swiftly-flowing water reference the nearby Chicago River, and are suspended within glass and a structure of charred wood symbolizing the Great Chicago Fire of 1871. As the luminous images appear in perpetual motion and the burned wood speaks of disaster, we are reminded of the impermanence of nature, while the steel framework and bolt system indicate man’s ability to rebuild that which has been destroyed. The artists were inspired by the efforts of Friends of the Chicago River, an organization dedicated to restoring the fragile eco-system of the Chicago River.  "	
Western-Brown	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/damen-brown-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41480	-87.688502	41.966163	Ellen Rothenberg	Camouflage Screen	Art glass with ceramic melting color	2007	"Ellen Rothenberg’s artwork was inspired by the commuters who use the Western station and the way in which they influence the station’s ever-changing appearance. Throughout the day as travelers pass by the windows they are highlighted by the shifting natural light. The artist’s camouflage pattern creates varying levels of opacity, producing shadows of figures and a dynamic, cinematic setting. "	
Damen-Brown	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/montrose-brown-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40090	-87.678639	41.966286	Ron Baron	American Tourister	Bronze	2008	"The components of Ron Baron’s whimsical sculptures contain a history accumulated through years of use. Assembled from bronze castings of assorted vintage briefcases, suitcases and chairs culled from thrift stores and yard sales, the sculptures appear from a distance to be furniture or stacked luggage, but closer inspection rewards viewers with the discovery of embedded dioramas of travel scenes."	
Montrose-Brown	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/irving-park-brown-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41500	-87.675047	41.961756	Jason Pickleman	MONT/ROSE: AREA	"Cast aluminum, vinyl decals"	2007	"Comprising 318 complete and partial letterforms of anodized aluminum, Jason Pickleman’s mural celebrates neighboring streets around the Montrose Brown Line station using the graphic language of wayfinding and commercial signage. Set in Neue Helvetica font, the street names are broken at odd lengths, stacked and repeated to create new word combinations that are both familiar and irregular"	
Irving Park-Brown	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/addison-brown-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41460	-87.674868	41.954521	"Juan Carlos Macias
Commonplaces"	Commonplaces	Venetian hand-cut glass mosaic	2008	"Inspired by the CTA Brown Line, the Irving Park station and the community they serve, artist Juan Carlos Macias’ murals contemplate the brief convergence of individuals in the course of their separate journeys. Like a microcosm of Chicago, the train is a space that remains familiar while faces and other details change from day to day. The station itself is a point of destination, intersection and departure for a heterogeneous mixture of people in which all are equal—a common place. "	
Addison-Brown	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/paulina-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41440	-87.674642	41.947028	Gregory Gomez	The Encrypted Inning	Sand-cast bronze and patina	2007	"The Encrypted Inning, Gregory Gomez’s relief sculpture installation, celebrates both the Chicago Cubs and the human capacity to communicate complex information via two-dimensional symbols. Using the traditional method of baseball score-keeping, the sculpture describes the top half of the sixth inning and the bottom half of the ninth inning of the May 14, 1969 baseball game between the Chicago Cubs and the San Diego Padres. Among the colorful roster of Cubs players were both Ernie Banks and Ron Santo, who helped the home team come from behind to win the game with a score of 3 to 2. The box score symbols, re-created here in bronze, are derived from samples of Cubs broadcaster Ron Santo’s own writing. The Padres’ sixth inning is represented on the interior façades of the elevator towers, facing the passenger platform, and the Cubs’ ninth inning is represented on the exterior façade of the east elevator tower. Cubs management was instrumental in procuring writing samples, and granted the artist permission to duplicate Mr. Santo’s writing.  "	
Paulina	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/paulina-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41310	-87.670907	41.943623	Barbara Cooper	Transitions	"Mosaic: Hand-cut glass, Sculpture: Riveted brass and stainless-steel sheeting"	2009	"Transitions comprises a suspended sculpture and a mosaic, which form an artistic dialogue. “Transitions is intended to mirror the fluid, ephemeral, high-energy cellular neighborhoods of the city and the connections and intersections between them, which public transportation facilitates…(it) references not only passage to different physical places, but also to other states of being and points in time.” -Barbara Cooper  "	
Paulina	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/paulina-3.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41310	-87.670907	41.943623						
Paulina	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/southport-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41310	-87.670907	41.943623						
Southport	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/southport-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40360	-87.663619	41.943744	Elizabeth Fraiberg	Green (North Wall) and Yellow (South Wall)	Transfer-printed glazed ceramic tile	2008	"The abstract imagery of these murals is derived from the artist’s own photographs of the neighborhood surrounding the Southport station, which she layered and transformed through digital collage. The yellow mural is meant to energize and inspire patrons on their commute into the Loop, while the green mural is intended to impart feelings of coolness and serenity as they return home. "	
Southport	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/belmont-brown-3.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40360	-87.663619	41.943744						
Belmont	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/belmont-brown-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41320	-87.65338	41.939751	Jerald Jacquard	Space Junction of Energ	"painted steel, mixed media"	1970	"Jerald Jacquard’s sculpture,  Space Junction of Energy , is a paradox; an abstract sculpture that describes the specific  event of mass passing through space. The artist’s intention is to energize the viewer’s mind through perception of the  ever-shifting composition of geometric forms. Formal yet animated, the sculpture is an arrangement of hollow geometric  shapes constructed of cut and welded sheet steel. A visual blanket of orange paint unifies the variable components and  emphasizes the internal balance and harmony of this dynamic composition "	
Belmont	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/belmont-brown-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41320	-87.65338	41.939751						
Belmont	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/wellington-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41320	-87.65338	41.939751						
Wellington	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/wellington-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41210	-87.653266	41.936033	Martin Donlin	Transience	Architectural glass: ceramic enamels fired into tempered glass	2009	"The larger-than-life-size, abstracted human silhouettes  in Martin Donlin’s art glass windows form a rhythmic  composition that represents the community passing  through the Wellington station. A band of smaller figures,  resembling passengers awaiting a train, spans the  width of the glass station front. With repeated viewing,  passengers will discover subtle elements within the  design that are not apparent at first glance."	
Wellington	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/fullerton-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41210	-87.653266	41.936033						
Fullerton	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/fullerton-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41220	-87.65286844	41.92530037	Derick Malkemus	Landslide	Cast bronze	2009	"Abstract, dynamic and impeccably detailed, Landslide, like all of Derick Malkemus’ work, is a three-dimensional  drawing—as significant for its lines as for its forms. Employing a unique visual vocabulary, the artist intends his work to be an expression through form, without narrative, to be appreciated without need for a verbal explanation."	
Fullerton	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/fullerton-3.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41220	-87.65286844	41.92530037						
Fullerton	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/armitage-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41220	-87.65286844	41.92530037						
Armitage	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/sedgwick-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40660	-87.652644	41.918217	Jon Gitelson	Chicago El Stories	Glass photographic tiles	2008	"Jon Gitelson’s mural for the Armitage Brown Line station showcases shared and personal histories of Chicago as related to the artist by Chicagoans and Brown Line passengers. Central to the glass mural is a collection of forty-five photographic images, determined by the artist’s own research, which function as dual portraits of the city and of the memories of its residents. Mr. Gitelson conducted a series of interviews at the Armitage Brown Line station in which he asked individual passengers to share memories of places or experiences within the City of Chicago that are of personal significance. Each interview was captured by the artist in an audio recording. The artist then visited and photographed the scene of each event, free of people, creating a unique portrait of each individual’s memory while also allowing viewers of the artwork to vicariously visit each location. Below each photograph is an excerpt of the related interview. Surrounding the central grouping of images, and referencing the geographic starting point for the artist’s interviews, is a black and white border depicting a street map of the community surrounding the Armitage station."	
Sedgwick	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/chicago-brown-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40800	-87.639302	41.910409	Carlos Dzine Rolon	Time is the Enemy (Revisited)	"Ventian glass, marble and stone mosaic"	2009	"Infused with a spirit of playful escapism, this mural offers a breath of otherworldly dimensions in a familiar setting. The texture of hand-cut Venetian glass, assembled in a traditional, painstaking process, contrasts with the animation and energy of the composition. Mirrored glass adds movement to this rhythmic and flowing work befitting Old Town’s history as an artistic and countercultural enclave. "	
Chicago-Brown	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/merchandise-mart-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40710	-87.635924	41.89681	B.J. Krivanek and Joel Breaux	Reflections Expressions Transformations	"Aluminum, powder-coated aluminum"	2009	"Each panel of this kinetic art installation pivots independently, allowing the artwork to constantly shift and change, like the surrounding streetscape, in response to wind currents and the vibrations of passing trains. The highly polished aluminum reflects and fragments light and shadow from surrounding buildings, objects and people. “Located within Chicago’s art gallery district, this public artwork symbolizes the process of creativity—where observations and experiences are transformed into expressions that are placed into a public arena.” —B.J. Krivanek"	
Merchandise Mart	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/howard-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40460	-87.633924	41.888969	Columbia College Photography Department	In Transit Gallery	Photo montage	2001	"Bringing art to the City of Chicago in the form of a photo montage, the Columbia College Photography department displays photography by Columbia College students. Located throughout the bridge that connects the north- and southbound platforms, the students’ photos have turned the station into a transit gallery. "	Adopt-A-Station
Howard	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/howard-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40900	-87.672892	42.019063	Carla Arocha and Stephane Schraenen	24/7	Stainless steel	2009	"Titled 24/7 , the sculpture suspended overhead celebrates the dynamic activity that occurs day and night in the Howard station. Circular stainless steel plates, polished to a mirror finish, are draped together using fasteners custom-designed by the artists. A pattern of laser-cut holes scatters across the surface of the plates creating secondary circular patterns. As one moves through the space of the sculpture, the perception of circles reflected within circles is intensified. "	
Howard	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/howard-3.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40900	-87.672892	42.019063						
Howard	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/roosevelt-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40900	-87.672892	42.019063						
Roosevelt	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/sox-35th-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41400	-87.62703141	41.86737853	Juan Angel Chavez and Corinne Peterson	Hopes and Dreams	Glass ceramic mosaic	2002	"This mosaic is largely made up of tiles created by adults and children during weekend workshops at the Field Museum in the summer of 1999. Participants were asked to carve images related to the themes of Project Millennium- Origins, Transitions, New Directions, Discovery and Technology. The artists then glazed, fired and assembled the “people tiles” into readable designs that formed a scenic collage of contemplative images from nature including clouds, plants, trees, forests, oceans, animals, birds, sunsets, earth and space. "	Chicago Public Art Group
Sox-35th	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/sox-35th-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40190	-87.630636	41.831191	Cody Hudson	Magic Numbers	"Art glass, anodized aluminum"	2006	"Magic Numbers, an artwork in three components, celebrates the mysticism and fanaticism associated with the Chicago White Sox baseball team. The stairway panels indicate significant calendar years, the total number of players, and retired jersey numbers during the 104 years of White Sox history (1902 – 2005). Enveloping the station elevator is a pattern of multi-colored stripes referencing team trivia including uniform colors and win/loss statistics by year. Certain stripes include a code of picture symbols representing more obscure trivial facts. This language of symbols is an invention of artist Cody Hudson, who believes CTA riders and White Sox fans will eventually break the code. "	Arts in Transit
Sox-35th	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/47th-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40190	-87.630636	41.831191						
47th-Red	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/47th-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41230	-87.63094	41.810318	Jo Hormuth	Canopy Lights	"Laser-cut Acrylite, aluminum"	2007	"Inspired by the sensation of walking down a tree-lined street, Jo Hormuth’s artwork lends color and shade to the platform, simulating the feeling of blossoming trees overhead. Acrylic panels in twelve colors were laser-cut into a repetitive pattern hand-drawn by Ms. Hormuth and then installed within the existing canopy. Panels in varying hues of red anchor the north and south ends of the platform, signifying the CTA Red Line. "	Arts in Transit
47th-Red	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/garfield-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41230	-87.63094	41.810318						
Garfield-Red	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/63rd-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41170	-87.631157	41.79542	Bernard Williams	Nexus Orbs	Hydro-cut anodized aluminum	2007	"Inspired by patterns and imagery found in nature, ancient cultures and tribal art, Bernard Williams developed a vocabulary of symbols to create a suspended sculpture and series of medallions affixed to the stationhouse windows. Each circular in shape, the symbols serve as a metaphor for the rhythm of the daily commute in which one begins and ends in the same place. "	Arts in Transit
63rd	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/69th-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40910	-87.630952	41.780536	Sabina Ott	A Red Line and a Cloud	Art glass	2007	"As the 63rd Street stationhouse seems to float above the expressway, Sabina Ott’s artwork appears to interact with the landscape of Chicago, momentarily suspending the viewer in the painted clouds. A Red Line and a Cloud is based on maps that turn and swirl, mimicking the view north from the stationhouse. The path of the CTA Red Line route anchors the center of this landscape of floating clouds and color.  "	Arts in Transit
69th	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/69th-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40990	-87.625724	41.768367	Preston Jackson	A Need to Remember	"Bronze, stainless steel"	2007	"This sculpture, in the shape of a two-sided screen, juxtaposes contemporary and historic imagery of African-American culture and daily life. A master of portraiture and storytelling, artist reston Jackson intends this artwork to be a history lesson and inspiration for the present and future. The sculpture juxtaposes streetscapes and images of days past with tender scenes of hair-braiding and imagery from nature."	Arts in Transit
69th	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/79th-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40990	-87.625724	41.768367						
79th	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/79th-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40240	-87.625112	41.750419	Stephen Marc	South Side Weave	"Art glass, aluminum"	2007	"Stephen Marc created these murals by combining historic photographs of the nearby community with his own images of the South Side, photographed during the year 2006. The photo-montages feature old and new images superimposed of landmarks including the Auburn Park Lagoon and the Mt. Herman Missionary Baptist Church. The landscape of Chicago provides the descriptive background while portraits and scenes of daily life animate these spaces. The theme of hair is featured prominently, with images of braids creating a patterned framework for each mural. "	Arts in Transit
79th	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/87th-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40240	-87.625112	41.750419						
87th	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/87th-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41430	-87.624717	41.735372	Jeff Zimmerman	The Shore	Art glass	2007	"Images of a man and woman appear to float within schools of fish in Jeff Zimmerman’s contemporary stained-glass windows. Inspired by the theme of migration, the artist relates the daily activity of riding the train to the life-cycle of fish. Although fish swim constantly in migration, they eventually return to their birthplace. Floating amongst the fish, the man and woman reach out to each other, as if bridging the gap between strangers in their daily journey."	Arts in Transit
87th	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/54th-cermak-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41430	-87.624717	41.735372						
54th/Cermak	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/kostne-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40580	-87.75669201	41.85177331	Nicole Gordon	54th/Cermak Station	Paint on porcelain tile	2004	"This painting on ceramic tile depicts a tapestry in which Cicero’s rich cultural history and diversity unfolds. Cicero is 
a town that is historically noted as a working class community composed primarily of immigrants that have strived to 
establish themselves and realize the American dream. A township map of Cicero serves as a foundation of the piece,  
as well as decorative references to the cultures that comprise the community. Some of the town’s most important streets 
and landmarks provide a structural element, upon which the narrative unfolds. "	Arts in Transit
Kostner	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/kostner-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40600	-87.733258	41.853751	Beatrice Coron	Seeds of the Future Planted Today	"Water jet cut stainless steel, four panels"	2004	"This project aims to plant seeds of thought. Icons of growth and transformation take root in the past to transform our future. In the center panel, young children are watering the city, representing hope for the future. The side panels reflect the importance of education and literacy as the open books at the bottom the pages sprout with plants, symbolizing human growth."	Arts in Transit
Kostner	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/pulaski-pink-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40600	-87.733258	41.853751						
Pulaski-Forest Park	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/central-park-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40920	-87.725663	41.873797	Adam Brooks	Pulaski Station	Mixed media mosaic with water jet cut glass in three panels	2004	"Adam Brooks uses quotes by individuals linked to Chicago to represent broad ideas about what it means to be human.  
The words of these contemporary figures create meaning within the site. The quotes in this artwork were chosen to reflect 
a wide-range approach to human thought and understanding. Each of the three individuals whose quotes are used – 
Muhammad Ali, James Cone and Haki Madhubuti – was a pioneer in his field. Muhammad Ali is the original archetype  
for the modern poet; James Cone is a minister, writer and a professor at the Union Theological Seminary in New York;  
Haki Madhubuti is a Chicago-based poet and publisher who founded the Third World Press."	Arts in Transit
Central Park	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/kedzie-pink-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40780	-87.714842	41.853839	Olivia Gude	Cannas and Corn: A Community Garden	Mixed media mosaic	2004	This mosaic commemorates the ephemeral public art form of the community garden. North Lawndale has an active tradition of dedicated people who transform abandoned urban spaces into neighborhood amenities. They describe their work as “blight into sight.” The mosaic was fabricated in a community mosaic workshop to “plant the seeds” of mosaic making skills in the community so that locally made public art can become part of the garden making process.	Arts in Transit
Kedzie-Cermak	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/california-pink-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41040	-87.705408	41.853964	John Himmelfarb	Coast of Chicago	Custom-shaped painted tiles	2004	"The neighborhood surrounding the Kedzie station is full of bustling activity. The ceramic tiles of this artwork reflect the strength of community as a whole, but also the uniqueness of its individual parts. Many of the design elements are drawn from architectural details of homes, schools and commercial buildings, as well as structural details associated with the CTA. These sources reflect the current community and give reference to the history of the neighborhood. Combined with this imagery are design elements inspired by connections of heritage to Mayan, Aztec and African cultures."	Arts in Transit
California-Cermak	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/california-pink-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40440	-87.694774	41.854109	Christopher Tavares Silva	Amor	Mixed media mosaic	2004	"The circular flight of birds from heart to heart 
suggests the passing of love from person to 
person and place to place, as well as the coming 
and going of passengers. The migration of birds 
from clear to rainy skies symbolically endorses 
the virtues of promoting love through times of both 
happiness and hardship."	Arts in Transit
California-Cermak	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/western-pink-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40440	-87.694774	41.854109						
Western-Cermak	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/western-pink-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40740	-87.685129	41.854225	Hector Duarte	Ice Cream Dream	Mixed media mosaic	2004	"At the center of this mosaic is a large heart with several buildings featuring the neighborhood’s unique architectural characteristics and facades. Surrounding the heart are the Willis Tower and John Hancock Center, signifying the neighborhood’s place in the city. Monarch butterflies are the predominant theme throughout the mural; like many people who pass through this station daily, monarchs are migrants.  Every year the monarch travels thousands of miles from Mexico to the Midwest. The butterflies emerge in the mural as a wave of energy, a reflection of magical realism that has marked Latin American literature."	Arts in Transit
Western-Cermak	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/damen-pink-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40740	-87.685129	41.854225						
Damen-Cermak	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/damen-pink-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40210	-87.675975	41.854517	Juan Angel Chavez	Vida Simple	Mixed media mosaic	2004	"Inspired by the neighborhood of Pilsen, this multi-media mosaic focuses on the individuality of the people that created the heritage and cultural identity of the community. The design itself is a collage of imagery taken from the neighborhood, including community member portraits, local street scenes and industrial wildlife – birds, small animals and plants that reside and grow in the industrial landscape."	Arts in Transit
Damen-Cermak	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/18th-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40210	-87.675975	41.854517						
18th	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/cumberland-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40830	-87.669147	41.857908	Francisco Mendoza; Gallery 37 students and the Mexican Museum of National Art	Untitled	Painted wall murals	1998	"Covering the steel panels of the station wall, several murals symbolize and tell stories about the neighborhood that the 18th station serves.  Each of the colorful murals illustrates a different story of rich Mexican heritage while also depicting many important cultural icons in Mexican history."	Adopt-A-Station
Cumberland	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/cumberland-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40230	-87.838028	41.984246	Charles Ross	Rock Bow	"Bronze, granite and liquid-filled acrylic"	1983	This mesmerizing sculpture is made of liquid-filled acrylic with a granite base and is located at the junction of the rail station and the bus terminal.  During the early mornings and late afternoons this sculpture projects large bands of color onto the walls and floor of the station whenever direct sunlight strikes the prism.	
Cumberland	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/harlem-blue-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40230	-87.838028	41.984246						
Harlem-O'Hare	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/harlem-blue-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40750	-87.8089	41.98227	Alex Katz	"Harlem Station, 1984"	Enamel on aluminum mural	1985	"Exhibiting an assortment of animated close-ups, this artwork is fabricated of enamel on aluminum and is located within the stationhouse, along the north window where it can be seen inside the station and from adjacent streets. Celebrating Chicago’s broad diversity, this mural is a reflection of the city’s hardworking people. "	
Harlem-O'Hare	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/pulaski-orange-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40750	-87.8089	41.98227						
Pulaski-Orange	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/pulaski-orange-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40960	-87.724493	41.799756	"Hector Duarte, Gallery 37 and Curie High School students"	Untitled	Mural on tile	1998	The painted mural on tile greets customers and they enter the station. The mural depicts a rose with petals made of many different flags that symbolize the many ethnic communities that make Chicago such a vibrant city.	Adopt-A-Station
Pulaski-Orange	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/conservatory-1.jpg""/></g></svg>"	40960	-87.724493	41.799756						
Conservatory	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/conservatory-2.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41670	-87.716523	41.884904	Carolyn Elaine 2002 and 2003; Salim Hurtado and Michael Cloud 2001; Nina Smoot-Cain 2004	Garfield Park Conservatory Mosaics	Ceramic tile mosaics	2001-2004	"Mounted on the bases of the elevators and pillars of the CTA tracks and station, these mosaics are made up of a colorful arrangement of cracked ceramic tiles. Designed to highlight local cultural and environmental themes, the mosaics enhance the viewers’ appreciation of the ‘L’ stop, the conservatory and the community. "	Adopt-A-Station and Chicago Public Art Group
conservatory	"<svg><g><img src =""http://www.transitchicago.com/assets/1/public_art/conservatory-3.jpg""/></g></svg>"	41670	-87.716523	41.884904						
conservatory	"<svg><g><img src =""""/></g></svg>"	41670	-87.716523	41.884904						
